Serxhio Gugo

Phone Number: 1–(203)–819–1259 – Email: gugoserxhio@gmail.com – Linkedin: Linkedin.com/in/serxhio-gugo – GitHub: https://github.com/SerxhioGugo

Website: https://serxhiogugo.co/

About Me

My name is Serxhio Gugo and I'm an iOS Engineer with 6 years of experience in Swift programming. I specialize in building practical and user-friendly iOS applications. I am fascinated by how mobile devices and applications influence our daily lives. I'm all about creating reliable and high-quality solutions. Beyond coding, I ensure that the apps I work on are thoroughly tested for smooth performance. I am eager to contribute my skills and passion for crafting exceptional mobile experiences.

Experience

iOS Engineer Sept 2020 - Present

Caesars Digital - Jersey City, NJ

- Developed Account Menu with 16+ journeys and used Deep linking to redirect the app to different journeys from our website. Integrated Caesars Rewards into the app.
- Built Registration/Login using multiple RESTful API's while implementing Email/Password/Address/Phone validation.
- Created completely re-usable and complex UI for SportsBook betting and integrated live data using WebSockets.
- Organized the app to account for multi-state while using GeoComply and CoreLocations to identify user location.
- Properly mocked and Unit Tested all my features, which lowered our bug results by 21%.

iOS Engineer Jun 2020 - Sept 2020

Gesture - New York, NY

- Worked closely with the back-end team to design and develop Gesture Happiness Delivered.
- Developed Event Planning feature using Firebase Cloud Messaging and Cloud Functions.
- Developed Phone number Authentication feature using Firebase and Twilio.

iOS Engineer July 2018 – Sept 2020

AppCrunch LTD - Remote

- Worked closely with the back-end team to design and develop Lollipop App.
- Develop the chat functionality of the app using Firebase.
- Implement camera functionality using AVFoundation.
- Refactoring of the base code from Objective-C to the latest Swift syntax.

Education

BMCC | Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science – GPA 3.8 **iOS Developer Bootcamp** | BrainStation Bootcamp – New York, NY | 2018–2019

Skills

iOS Development

- Swift, SwiftUI, UIKit, AVFoundation, CoreLocation, WebSockets
- RESTful API's, URLSession, Codable, Combine, MVC / MVVM / Coordinator Pattern
- Multithreading, GCD, Memory Management
- Unit Testing XCTest / Zephyr for Jira
- CI/CD Pipeline/Fastlane/NewRelic/GitLab, Agile/Scrum Jira/Confluence

Projects

CryptoNews - GitHub - https://bit.ly/3fgkP6E